<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on Patricia Sandoval</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on Patricia Sandoval</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>XVI. Prepositions</title>
      <link>/post/post-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 22:20:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/post-16/</guid>
      <description>For the correct write in English you must know the correct use of every prepositions in English grammar and this could be a little confuse.
A preposition is a word used to link nouns, pronouns or phrases with other words in a sentences. The prepositions can change depending of the context, situation or time that you want to express.
If we want simplify this problem we can clasified in 3 parts:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XV. Nouns</title>
      <link>/post/post-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 16:20:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/post-15/</guid>
      <description>The nouns are the basic buildings blocks of a a sentence. there are person, things, animals, emotions, places, thoughts. In a sentence we could describe a thing and that thing is know as nouns.
With nouns exist a several rules that we need to know when we want to express something in a sentence with correct form. With nouns we have counts and non-counts nouns.
What is this??
Nouns are classsified in counts, this mean that we can count the noun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XIV. Pronouns</title>
      <link>/post/post-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 11:17:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/post-14/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes in a text, we need to replace a noun with other word because sometimes could be repetitive the use of the same noun in the same sentence. For example, this could be one situation that can explain this topic: &amp;ldquo;Maria is the best student of the class but he doesn´t know anything about sport and because of that her have the worst qualification of all the class&amp;rdquo;. Look like we refer Maria in two occasion with &amp;ldquo;Her&amp;rdquo;, her is a pronoun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XIII. Phrasal verbs</title>
      <link>/post/post-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 09:17:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/post-13/</guid>
      <description>In English, we have another type of verb and this are known as phrasal verbs. These groups of verbs generally have two words like this &amp;ldquo; Get up&amp;rdquo;(compound noun). With intuition you can say that the meaning of this verb is something like this: &amp;quot;put something up&amp;quot;, but is not, and because of that we need to be careful!.
Phrasal verbs have special meaning and for the person who is trying to learn English this could be a little tricky but with some practice, we can learn some of these verbs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XII. Comparatives and superlatives.</title>
      <link>/post/post-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 22:17:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/post-12/</guid>
      <description>In english when we need compare two things we can use comparatives and If we need to compare more than two we use superlatives.
Comparatives use er and superlatives use est
Example:
 This university of north of california is better than the university of south.
 The fruit in this place is more expensive than in the other place.
  Rules When we have one or two syllable word, like this: Spicy, big.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XI. Participles adjectives</title>
      <link>/post/post-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 18:30:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/post-11/</guid>
      <description>In the last topic, we develop what is an adjective, the structure of a sentence with an adjective and how we could make to use this adjective in a correct order now we go to talk about participles adjectives.
What is a participle adjective?:
The differences in meaning in &amp;quot;Ing&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Ed&amp;quot;.  When we develop the types of verbal tense and his meaning we say that present participle in a verb is built with Ing and the past participle is build with Ed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>X.  Adjectives</title>
      <link>/post/post-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 14:30:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/post-10/</guid>
      <description>Now, when we need describe a noun we use adjectives:
 The boy is very big  In this sentence, the adjective is &amp;ldquo;Big&amp;rdquo;. But why?
Because this world describe a noun, in this sentences the noun is a boy. Adjectives can describe singular or plural nouns and can describe pronouns.
 They have a big cat  They is a pronoun. (Pronoun is the same thing that a noun, we talk about this topic in another topic).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IX. Gerunds and Infinitives</title>
      <link>/post/post-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 12:30:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/post-9/</guid>
      <description>In this moment you should be able to know what means the verb plus ing. you can say that is the form of the verb present participle but also we can say that is a gerund.
Gerunds are verbs plus ing. the differences between all the other topic that we develop is that in this case, they not acting like verbs in a sentences actually, they can act as nouns, subject or the object in a sentences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VIII. Modals verbs </title>
      <link>/post/post-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 17:30:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/post-8/</guid>
      <description>Modals verbs we can use when we need to express ability, possibility, advice or imposibility. This type of verbs are like helping verbs in a sentence because they are always accompanied by the main verb.
When we use these type of verb the main verb mainteing their original form:
 She can go to the pool.
 My father was able to run 5 milles everyday in the morning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VII. Past perfect continuous</title>
      <link>/post/post-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 16:30:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/post-7/</guid>
      <description>This verbal tense look similar with present perfect progressive, but in this verbal tense we talk about an action or situation that develop in one moment different that right now. With this verbal tense, we can talk about activities or actions that occurs in the past and continues happen in the past tense and just like in present perfect progressive we can use since and for, with this, we can make reference about that the activity was had not finished in that time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VI. Past Perfect</title>
      <link>/post/post-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 10:30:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/post-6/</guid>
      <description>When we talk about and action that happened in the past but also we need to show that this action develops in the past before the recent past we can use the past perfect. This definition could be a little confused but we can see better with an example:(example1)
 When John came to home, I had eaten the dinner.  The estructure of this verbal tense is the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>V. Present perfect VS Present perfect progressive</title>
      <link>/post/post-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 23:30:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/post-5/</guid>
      <description>In the last topic we develop the verbal tense know as present perfect continuous but for the student could be confused the differences and the correct use between the present perfect (is the first topic explained)and present perfect continuous. The reason for this is we can to express and action or event with present perfect and present perfect continuous and in the two forms is correct but because of that it is important to know the differences and similarities between this verbal tense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>III. Static Verbs</title>
      <link>/post/post-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 23:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/post-3/</guid>
      <description>In English, if you want to express and state, thoughts, emotions, or senses we can use stative verbs. This verbs like the title said, express states. It is important pay attention!!! this type of verbs cannot used for describe actions, or in continuous form (continuous is a verbal tense, that we have discussed more them (Ing)).
We can categorize this verbs  Thoughts: Believe, agree, remember, understand, prefer, know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IV. Present perfect continuous</title>
      <link>/post/post-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 23:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/post-4/</guid>
      <description>When we need to express the development of an ACTIVITY that began in the past and progress right now. We can use the present perfect progressive, also we can use this type of verbal tense when we want to express the duration of the activity. With continuous we have use &amp;ldquo;Ing&amp;rdquo; at the end of the main verb in the sentence that is known as the present participle form of the verbs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>II. Adverbs</title>
      <link>/post/post-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 22:40:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/post-2/</guid>
      <description>In the first point, we develop the verbal tense known as present perfect. In this verbal tense frequently used adverbs (just like another verbal tense).
Adverbs are word that accompanies the verbs in sentences. They modify the meaning of the verb.
For the moment I want to put like example the following adverbs:
Ever, Never, Yet, Already
With the adverb Ever we can express an experienced at some time in your life:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I. Present Perfect</title>
      <link>/post/post-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 22:30:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/post-1/</guid>
      <description>When we need to talk about actions and events that start in the past without a specific time and that action in the present has relevance we can express these with the verbal tense known as present perfect.This is an example about the use of present perfect:
They have met in the classroom.
It is important remember that this verbal tense can not use when we need to express actions with specific time about when are happened this.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>